江淮大地洒下了他们辛勤的汗水
From Jianghuai Plain to Loessial Highland
黄土高坡衬托着他们粗犷的身姿
from snow covered Northern  China to Western Gobi Desert
北国冰雪映照过他们坚毅的脸颊
everywhere over the vast land of China remain their persistence of seeking
戈壁沙漠留下过他们坚实的脚印
footprints of pioneering and passion of hard working
他们是一个输送温暖与光明的神奇部落
They're the kind of heroes bringing others warmth and
light by working day and night to wake up coal treasures
sleeping under the deep ground from millions of years ago
他们披星戴月 餐风宿露 所到之处
Wherever they are, the wild would be no longer dead silent
荒漠不再无烟 大地不再沉寂
the deserted turn to be vibrant with life
沉睡地下亿万年的宝藏被唤醒
barren land full of hope
点石成金的古老传说又有了新的演绎
They are giving new interpretation to the legend of Gold Touch
他们以 唤醒宝藏 勘建华夏，造福人类
Keeping the sacred mission in mind tapping coal treasure
to benefit people and the nation
为神圣使命 用智慧 勇气 激情 人格与魅力
they have worked out miracles one after another with wisdom
and courage, passion, sense
在神州大地上创造一个又一个辉煌
of responsibility and self-sacrifice
他们是煤炭战线的一支尖兵
They are regarded as pioneers
他们是地勘行业的一朵奇葩
and wonder makers in China’s coal prospecting industry